<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WindNext on WindNext Energy - Modular wind turbines that unlock the next chapter of wind power generation</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/windnext/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WindNext on WindNext Energy - Modular wind turbines that unlock the next chapter of wind power generation</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:49:30 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/windnext/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Safe for birds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/safe-for-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:49:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/safe-for-birds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-global-problem&#34;&gt;A global problem&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem of bird and bat fatalities due to wind turbines has been well documented. Often, it forms the basis for the local community opposition to installation of new wind turbine farms. The need for a wildlife safe solution is particularly prevalent in areas of the world where there is a huge&#xA;wind power potential, but limited areas develop wind farms due to wildlife conservation. There have been innovations designed to deflect bats&#xA;and birds to reduce risk, usch as ultrasonic boom boxes, darker painted blades, radar detection of flocks that cause turbine shut downs and similar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WindNext technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/windnext-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/windnext-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;challenges with existing turbines (extreme wind, large, cannot recycle)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;windnext solution&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;modular&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;assembled on-site&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;fully recyclable&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;technical details (flow speed increased etc)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60 years lifetime&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-windnext&#34;&gt;Why WindNext?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WindNext team started thinking about new ways to generate wind power while seeing the challenges of building existing systems. It is often hard to place wind farms in existing landscape, as the locations with good wind conditions are rare. The local population is also often against new wind farms due to the annoying infrasound and the deadly effect they can have on the local bird populations. The wind turbines themselves are also not very green - they last only 20 years and the giant fiberglass blades are almost impossible to recycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
