<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WindNext Energy - Modular wind turbines that unlock the next chapter of wind power generation</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on WindNext Energy - Modular wind turbines that unlock the next chapter of wind power generation</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:49:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WindNext technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/windnext-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/windnext-technology/</guid>
      <description>A closer look into the technology behind WindNext</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized for hills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/optimized-hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:49:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/optimized-hills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/posts/turbines-on-hill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;WindNext installation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hill-locations-are-still-untapped-but-need-better-technology&#34;&gt;Hill locations are still untapped, but need better technology&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hills have the best onshore wind potential to meet growind demand for wind power, but there are also challenges: often, there is no space for installation and transportation of large turbine parts is either expensive or simply impossible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With demand for wind power growing and legacy wind power technology reaching the limits of deployment potential, the time is ripe for a new technology that will enable future growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe for birds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/safe-for-birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:49:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/safe-for-birds/</guid>
      <description>WindNext turbine design make it the safest wind turbine for birds and bats</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero infrasound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/no-infrasound/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:47:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/no-infrasound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;infrasound-and-its-effects-on-humans-and-animals&#34;&gt;Infrasound and its effects on humans and animals&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Infrasound is sound with very long wavelengths, a planar wave structure and outside the range of normal hearing for moderate sound pressure levels. The attenuation of infrasound is complex; it initially increases with distance from the source (becoming quieter), but it can decrease over still further distances so that it then gets louder. When it interacts with buildings, it can produce secondary structural vibrations that may be perceptible to the occupants. Infrasound from wind turbines is particularly annoying because the sound signature contains short, frequent episodes and it persists over extended periods, compared with other short-duration sources (such as trains). Most people can ‘tune out’ repeated sounds but in some people the central nervous system becomes sensitized and they suffer the symptoms of chronic noise stress such as anxiety, depression, cognitive dysfunction and disrupted sleep (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2210670722006126&#34;&gt;source: Wind turbine infrasound: Phenomenology and effect on people, ScienceDirect&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3x ROI - our pilot project in-depth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/pilot-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 21:40:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/05/01/pilot-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-technology&#34;&gt;Current technology&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern wind turbines have over 8,000 parts and blades as long as 70 meters. The rise in turbine size also increases stress and load on the structure. All of this leads to the projected life span of 20 years. After that, the teardown is costly and a lot of the parts, like the blades, are challenging to recycle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;windnext-approach&#34;&gt;WindNext approach&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to their smaller size, WindNext modules are by definition less efficient. To make economic sense, this lower efficiency had to be addressed. Our designers worked hard to deliver a solution that makes up for lower efficiency by extending the lifetime of the module by up to 3x to 60 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;interested-in-windnext&#34;&gt;Interested in WindNext?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Email to info (at) windnext-energy.com to get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-to-do-if-i-have-still-not-received-the-order&#34;&gt;1. WHAT TO DO IF I HAVE STILL NOT RECEIVED THE ORDER?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/1/01/01/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/1/01/01/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;move-static-content-to-static&#34;&gt;Move static content to &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; will be copied as-is to the &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; output. Hugo keeps all static content under &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;. You should therefore move it all there.&#xA;With Jekyll, something that looked like&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/&#xA;    ▾ images/&#xA;        logo.png&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;should become&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/&#xA;    ▾ static/&#xA;        ▾ images/&#xA;            logo.png&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt;) to be moved to &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
